<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Computer Vision | Steven Lang</title><link>/tag/computer-vision/</link><atom:link href="/tag/computer-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Computer Vision</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/icon_hu1e660c1c67a167d0d71efce89dcd67c3_18860_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Computer Vision</title><link>/tag/computer-vision/</link></image><item><title>Oriented Object Detection using a One-Stage Anchor-Free Deep Model</title><link>/project/master-thesis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/master-thesis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Master Thesis at the TU Darmstadt in the AIML Lab supervised by &lt;a href="https://ml-research.github.io/people/kkersting/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof. Kristian Kersting&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.ml.informatik.tu-darmstadt.de/people/fventola/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fabrizio Ventola&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Object detection is a fundamental task in computer vision. While substantial
progress in the field of axis-aligned bounding-box detection has been made, it
suffers from poor performance on oriented objects, resulting in large parts of
the bounding box covering non-object related area. Therefore, the recent field
of oriented object detection has emerged, generalizing object detection to
arbitrary orientations which are commonly found in e.g. aerial view imagery or
security camera footage. This enables a tighter fit of bounding boxes, leading
to a better separation of bounding boxes especially in cases of dense object
distributions. In this work we present DAFNe: a Dense one-stage
Anchor-Free deep Network for oriented object detection. As one-stage model,
DAFNe performs predictions on a dense grid over the input image, being
architecturally simpler in design, as well as easier to optimize than their
two-stage alternatives. Being an anchor-free model, DAFNe additionally
reduces the prediction complexity by refraining from bounding box anchors
which come with many burdens: anchor specifications need more attentive
hyper-parameter fine-tuning on a per-dataset basis, increased model size and
computational overhead. Moreover, we introduce a novel vectorized corner
sorting algorithm to efficiently represent bounding boxes with a canonical
corner ordering batch-wise, an orientation-aware center-ness formulation for
arbitrary oriented bounding boxes to down-weight low-quality predictions, and
a center-to-corner bounding-box prediction strategy that improves object
localization performance. Our experiments show that DAFNe outperforms
all previous one-stage anchor-free models on DOTA 1.0, to the best of our
knowledge. DAFNe improves the prediction accuracy over the previous
best results by 4.65% mAP, setting the new state-of-the-art results by
achieving 76.95% mAP.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GAN based Food Interpolation</title><link>/project/food-interpolator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/food-interpolator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Deep Generative Models Course Project at TU Darmstadt.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="goal">Goal&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The main goal of this project is to learn a conditional GAN that can interpolate between different types of food.
We want to achieve fluid transitions between e.g.:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Burger &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Pizza&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="data">Data&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Scraped from google with &lt;a href="https://github.com/hardikvasa/google-images-download" target="_blank" rel="noopener">google-images-download&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Partly from &lt;a href="http://pizzagan.csail.mit.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PizzaGAN&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="results">Results&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Video results can be found &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LndGGbR4uxY&amp;amp;list=PLVCWvLHvDaenJrE2N-Akwo7-1kGN5vd5W" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="progressive-growing-video">Progressive Growing (Video)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/V7n1M14jKPM" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/V7n1M14jKPM/hqdefault.jpg" width="50%">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="pizza-to-pizza-video">Pizza to Pizza (Video)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/MSPZ56zy-OU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/MSPZ56zy-OU/hqdefault.jpg" width="50%">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="burger-to-burger-video">Burger to Burger (Video)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/LndGGbR4uxY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/LndGGbR4uxY/hqdefault.jpg" width="50%">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="random-latent-space-video">Random Latent Space (Video)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/n0ucsR-ko60" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/n0ucsR-ko60/hqdefault.jpg" width="50%">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="code-base">Code Base&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The code is based on a &lt;a href="https://github.com/jalola/improved-wgan-pytorch" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PyTorch implementation&lt;/a> of &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1704.00028" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Improved Training of Wasserstein GAN&lt;/a> and a &lt;a href="https://github.com/jeromerony/Progressive_Growing_of_GANs-PyTorch" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PyTorch implementation of Progressive Growing of GANs&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unsupervised Monocular Depth Estimation using Atrous Convolutions</title><link>/project/monodepth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/monodepth/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Monocular depth estimation is concerned with computing a dense depth map from a single image, but faces difficulties especially at object boundaries. Atrous convolutions have been successfully employed to this end in the task of semantic segmentation. In this paper we investigate, whether it is also possible to apply atrous convolutions in unsupervised monocular depth estimation. Specifically, we place an Atrous Spatial Pyramid Pooling block in a convolutional neural network between the encoder and decoder. This block allows for computing feature maps at different spatial scales on top of the encoder output. Our experiments show that atrous convolutions in the proposed setup do not improve depth estimation performance. Furthermore, the necessity of a lower output stride after the encoder, such that an increased receptive field size is even applicable, harms runtime and increases memory consumption. Finally, we show that it is possible to reduce the number of channels after the encoder, which reduces the parameter count without impairing predictions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Project on &lt;em>Unsupervised Monocular Depth Estimation Using Atrous Convolutions&lt;/em> in the Practical Course for Deep Learning in Computer Vision at TU Darmstadt.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep Feature Interpolation</title><link>/project/deep-feature-interpolation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/deep-feature-interpolation/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="description">Description&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Project on the Implementation of the Deep Feature Interpolation for Image
Content Changes &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1611.05507" target="_blank" rel="noopener">paper&lt;/a> in tensorflow together
with &lt;a href="https://www.numerik.mathematik.uni-mainz.de/manfred-faldum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Manfred Faldum&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal of deep feature interpolation is to add a specific target feature to
the face of a person. This may be a Mustache or a smiling mouth. The procedure
starts with taking &lt;code>k&lt;/code> images of people with the feature and &lt;code>k&lt;/code> images of
people without the feature. These sets (positive/negative) are the input to an -
on IMAGENET pretrained - VGG19 network. The output of each image is then fetched
at the Relu layers of the third, fourth and fifth convolutional block. This
builds a deep feature representation of an image. The deep feature vector of the
target feature is then calculated by taking the difference of the mean of the
positive and the negative set. To add the target feature to a new image, the
target feature vector in the deep feature space will be added to the deep
feature representation of this image. The image will then be restored by reverse
mapping the deep feature values into the original pixel space, using an
optimizer of your choice and the following loss function:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$$
z = argmin_z \frac{1}{2}||\left(\phi\left(x\right) + \alpha w\right) - \phi \left( z \right)||_2^2 + \lambda_{V^\beta} R_{V^\beta}\left(z\right)
$$
$$
R_{V^\beta}\left(z\right) = \sum_{i,j}\left( \left(z_{i,j+1} - z_{i,j}\right)^2 + \left(z_{i+1,j} - z_{i,j}\right)^2 \right)
$$&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where $z$ is the new image, $x$ is the input image, $\phi$ is the mapping into deep feature space, $\alpha$ is a scalar and $w$ is the deep feature vector of the target feature.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>