<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Machine Learning | Steven Lang</title><link>/tag/machine-learning/</link><atom:link href="/tag/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Machine Learning</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/icon_hu1e660c1c67a167d0d71efce89dcd67c3_18860_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Machine Learning</title><link>/tag/machine-learning/</link></image><item><title>Machine Learning Based Prediction of Half-Lives of Environmental Pollutants</title><link>/project/bachelor-thesis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/bachelor-thesis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bachelor Thesis at the JGU Mainz in the Research Group Data-Mining, supervised by &lt;a href="https://www.datamining.informatik.uni-mainz.de/stefan-kramer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof. Dr. Stefan Kramer&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://unidirectory.auckland.ac.nz/people/profile/j-wicker" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dr. Joerg Wicker&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Estimating degradation times of molecules, that possibly end up in the environment, is an important aspect for a wide range of industries. They have to take into account regulations that set a legal limit on half-lives of potential harmful molecules used in e.g. drugs or pesticides. This thesis addresses this by building machine learning models for the prediction of environmental pollutant&amp;rsquo;s half-lives. The recently released Eawag-Soil dataset of compounds and environmental conditions is used to explore possible influences on the molecule&amp;rsquo;s persistence. Moreover, a novel neural network architecture is proposed that takes advantage of the bi-relational data scheme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The results indicate that the dataset does either not have enough environmental variables or not enough combinations of compounds with degradation scenarios to explore the influences of the environmental conditions on the half-life times.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>